♪ In the
not too distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can
find, la la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot Roll Call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Tom Servo! ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science
facts, la la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself ♪
♪ It's just a show I
should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(doors clank)
- [Announcer] 30 seconds
to commercial sign.
- Hey, everybody,
it's me, it's Joel,
I'm marooned out in outer space,
and now you're trapped
in the vacuum with me.
The robots are throwing
me a little party today.
- [Announcer] Commercial
sign in 15 seconds.
- We're expecting a call
from the evil scientists
who shot us into space for
the invention exchange.
But until then, we're
gonna party like it's 1990.
- [Announcer] Commercials sign
in five, four, three, two.
Commercial sign now.
- We're gonna be
back in a matter
of seconds, so stick around.
(upbeat theme music)
Hey, what did you guys spike
this punch with, anyway?
- It's 10W 30 and Tang.
- Ugh.
Act like your parents are home,
the scientists are calling.
- Come in, Joel, my little
free floating clambake.
- Hey sir, what happened to you?
- Well, we had a little
mishap in the lab this week.
We were trying to make
a cold fusion Walkman,
and I don't know
what happened, but.
You see what happened
Anyway, Dr, Forrester
will be here in a second,
he's just trying to make
himself look presentable.
Just make with the invention
exchange, wild boy.
- Oh, okay, well.
This is an invention in
honor of the party today,
that the robots are throwing.
When I was a boy, I used
to play with one of these.
All right.
And now, I'm a man, all right?
What's your invention, sir?
- It's, nevermind.
Are you okay, Clay?
- Yes, Larry.
Remember, it's all in
the name of science.
Well, Joel, I guess our
little experiment this week
is going to be a
powerful healing salve
that will allow us to regain
our rugged good looks,
- Maybe our hair.
- Nothing wrong
with my hair, Larry,
- Jeepers.
You guys look like something
from a Wes Craven's
children's book.
- [Both] Thank you.
- Well, your film today, Joel
is called Black Scorpion.
It's a Mexican film with
effects by Ray Harryhousen,
the man who brought you The
Seven Voyages of Sinbad.
- It's filled with
blue screen action
and jerky monster movement.
But at least there's no
recognizable talent in it.
Enjoy.
- Oh we got movies!
(doors clank)
Man those scientists
really looked terrible.
- [Crow] Hey it's
Krakatoa, east of Java.
Fentonville, east of Muncie!
- [Joel] Is that a
crack house or what?
- [Tom] Cops is
filmed on location.
Everything you see is true.
- [Crow] Yellowstone, 1988
Fire lay waste over 700,000
acres of pristine virgin pines.
Only one man can
fight these flames.
Fred Adair.
- [Tom] Fred Astaire?
- [Joel] Hey it's
Universal Studios.
- [Announcer] Wreck their
homes and destroy their lives.
- [Tom] Beams.
- [Announcer] And
so today again they
kneel terrified and helpless
as a new volcano is created
by the mysterious and
rebellious forces of nature.
- [Crow] Horny broad voiced
announcer uses his mighty voice
to put fear in
the viewer's mind.
- [Announcer] Whole
acres of rich farmland
have cracked and
dropped from sight.
And millions of
tons of molten lava
are roaring down the slopes.
- [Joel] Guys get out of the
way, that's why you're dying!
- [Announcer] Mexico as the
most violent of modern times.
To the benighted citizenry
of this remote countryside.
- [Crow] Let's
make s'mores later.
- [Joel] Okay.
- [Tom] Did you bring the Kraut?
- [Crow] No I left
them in the Volvo.
- [Announcer] Having
reached a towering height
of 9,000 feet within a few days.
- [Tom] And then tragedy struck,
we ran out of stock footage.
- [Announcer] But what
is now most feared.
- Is it soup yet?
- Is that rescue work will be
severely hampered
by the hazardous
inaccessibility of the terrain.
- [Joel] The wavy title.
- [Tom] Something
tells me this movie
is about our friendly
neighbors to the south.
- [Crow] Tom there's
no south in space.
- [Tom] Carlos Muzquiz.
Pascual Peña.
Fanny Schiller.
Pedro Galvan.
Duncan and Blees.
Lindon.
- [Crow] Edmond Fitzgerald?
This must be his wreck.
- That's Edward.
- Oh.
- [Tom] Sawtell.
Melford and Dietz.
And Ludwig.
(dramatic music)
Now junior. we're just looking
for a place to picnic here.
Now I know Gary's buried
around here some place.
Look around for
that shallow grave.
- There she is.
Mom?
Yeah.
- [Tom] Shucks, it looks
like a volcano to me.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Hey why
does he need a pipe?
Why doesn't he just
suck in some air?
- [Tom] Feel the pumice power
go to work on your lungs.
- That volcano looks as
far away as it ever did.
- Nobody stuck a
gun on your back
to make you become a geologist.
- Yeah but you don't
have to rub it in.
- [Tom] Hey look, it looks like
it's from the old MASH set.
- You know if
there was any other
village within 50 miles of here
a sign like this
could confuse people.
- [Crow] I don't get it.
- Looks like somebody else
has been through here lately.
- Yeah, army truck
maybe, police.
- [Crow] Hey wait that's
my motorman's helper.
- Don't get me wrong Doc, I love
this Mexico of yours but.
- [Joel] I like
my Mexico better.
Got a little plastic
burro, it's neat.
- How did you get
permission so fast?
For my group I mean.
After all, red tape
and that sort of thing.
- Simple, just told
them the truth.
That you needed me
along as an interpreter.
- [Crow] And to
mop up your sweat.
- [Doc] Well that may be
true but I think the language
you really spoke best was
with our secretary who secured
all the documents for you.
- Oh I didn't use
Spanish with her.
- [Joel] I used Greek, it really
confused the hell out of her.
- Incredible.
Truly isn't it?
- [Crow] What the
screen behind us?
- May be as severe
as Mount Pele.
- [Crow] This driving effect?
- San Francisco.
Lucky there are so
few people up here.
- Well there were enough.
- [Tom] Meanwhile.
on a pole somewhere.
- [Joel] Oh hiya linesman.
- How far have you come fellas?
- Mexico City we left on Monday.
- Where did you want to go?
- San Lorenzo.
How far is it, do you know?
- Who knows how the bridges are.
- The bridge is far
- Maybe a couple of hours.
- A police car went by
just before sundown.
They didn't come back, so
maybe they got through okay.
- Was San Lorenzo hurt badly?
- Who knows?
The telephone lines are
down since the earthquake.
- Thanks a lot.
See you later.
- Take it easy.
- [Crow] Goodbye, see you later.
Auf wiedersehen.
Hasta luego.
(wind howls)
- [Joel] Boy am I hungry.
Is that my stomach
growling or yours?
- What the devil was that?
- I don't know.
- Ordinarily I've got nothing
against moonlight nights
but I'll be glad
to get by this one.
- [Tom] What kind of
oil mixture do you use?
- Looks like a
farmhouse up ahead,
maybe we can get
some water up there?
- I hope so I'd like to save
those last two bottles of beer.
♪ Two bottles of beer in the
Jeep, two bottles of beer ♪
♪ Pass one down,
pass it around ♪
♪ Beer in the Jeep. ♪
- [Joel] I'll just move
this high voltage power line
with this piece of metal.
Let me dip it in water first.
(upbeat theme music)
- A little gas station
never looked better.
- Hello!
Anybody home?
- I'll see if I
can find the well.
(dramatic music)
Hey hello in there!
- [All] Hello out there!
Nope, we don't need a Jeep.
- Hey, hi!
- Hi!
- Come here!
Look at this.
- [Joel] So it's
a pile of bricks.
See them all the time.
- [Crow] Hey another
pile of bricks.
and a card that says "Black
Scorpion Wrecking Services".
What could it mean?
- Look at that!
- [Joel] Wow it's a car!
- [Tom] Hey that'd
make a cool Ford.
- [Joel] Yeah it's a '55 Ford.
With a little work
could be cherry.
Yeah we chop it, drop it.
add some thresh pipes,
it'll be great.
- Certainly have no idea what
could've happened or why.
- What could do this
to a car out here?
- [Crow] Well I'm no
insurance adjuster
but a big truck or the
neighbor kids could've.
- [Operator] Calling 511.
Do you read me?
Sergeant Vega, do you read me?
This is headquarters calling.
- [Joel] Hey there's a
small man in the glove box.
help me find his torso.
- Hello?
Hello do you read me?
- [Operator] 511, I
read you Sergeant Vega.
What's your location?
- [Tom] I'm in the front seat
but I'm not Sergeant Vega.
- Take this, you're
head man down here.
- Hello?
Go ahead please.
- This is Arturo Ramos,
Professor of Geology
from the university.
My associate and I came
upon this patrol car.
There has been an accident.
I believe we're a
few kilometers south
of the village of San Lorenzo.
- [Operator] Where's
Sergeant Vega?
- He's not here.
No one is here.
The car is badly damaged
but there's no blood.
- [Operator] Did the
car run off the road?
- [Crow] There is no road.
- Didn't the police
sergeant make
a report after the accident?
The radio's working.
- [Operator] No we
have heard nothing.
Thank you professor, leave
the patrol car as it is.
We shall order
military intelligence
to send an emergency unit
to San Lorenzo immediately.
- We will.
- [Joel] Thank you for ordering.
Your total is $5.54,
please pull ahead to the
second drive thru
window, thank you.
- Not doing any good here pal.
(rattling)
- Hank.
Some of my countrymen may like
rattlesnakes in the house,
I can do without them.
- Let's take a look.
- [Joel] Funny,
that guy kills me.
- [Tom] Bob if you die
can I have your hat?
- [Joel] You know
this would make
an excellent
miniature golf course.
- [Crow] Hey look back here.
There's a key light.
- [Joel] This house is
filled with Christmas trees!
- [Tom] 10 bucks a foot?
Jesus.
(rattling)
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Well at
least we know they're
an advanced civilization,
they got Vicks VapoRub.
- [Crow] Yeah now
you're supposed to
pick it up with your forearms
and leave the monastery forever.
You can walk on the rice paper.
- [Tom] Bob look baby tracks.
- [Crow] What's
behind the curtain?
- [Tom] It's a baby boy!
- [Crow] All right
kid start talking
- [Joel] Come on now,
it's just a baby.
- That rattlesnake is the
worst kind of them all.
- [Tom] Let's blast it.
- [Hank] Come on fella.
- [Crow] Hey how'd he
know his name was Fella?
- You have practice Mr Scott?
- [Joel] I used to be Mrs Scott.
- With four brothers
and two sisters.
- [Tom] Wait a minute,
they were older than me.
- What do you suppose
caused this wreck,
that police car out there?
- Could've been a bull.
- If it was then it had
to be the grand pappy
of the biggest
bull that ever was.
- [Tom] The Schlitz
Malt Liquor Bull.
Wow the grass even
- Yeah so?
- Look I've already got half a
dozen questions I can't answer
I try to ignore any new ones.
- You think we
oughta use the radio
to tell them about the kid?
- No I think we ought to get to
San Lorenzo as quick as we can.
Look at this kid.
Not a peep out of him.
- [Crow] Peep.
- You know if I ever
have any of my own
I think I'll feed him
beans and tortillas too.
I'll be able to get
some sleep nights.
- [Joel] I doubt it.
(wind howls)
- [Tom] No more beans and
tortillas for that kid.
- Hey, wait a minute.
- [Joel] I'll just leave him
here on the seat of the car.
- [Crow] What's
behind this tree?
It's a dead cop!
- [Tom] That's right Bob
it's a 1953 Señor Policia,
complete with 38
snub nose revolver,
dilated pupils and rigor mortis.
You too will sleep silently
in your own Señor Policia.
- [Joel] From Spiegel Catalog,
Chicago Illinois 60609.
- [Crow] Funny place
for a wax museum
- [Joel] He's dead you idiot.
- [Crow] I got a
wax museum in my ear
- [Joel] I told him
not to eat the worm.
- Hello, hello?
- We only found Sergeant
Vega and the baby.
- [Operator] I have
that professor.
Right you said Vega's revolver
had all chambers fired?
- Yes all.
- [Operator] At what?
- We wish we knew too.
- [Operator] Thank you again.
The emergency unit will be
in San Lorenzo tomorrow.
- [Crow] They're sending
a eunuch to San Lorenzo?
- [Joel] What do you think
that announcer looks like?
I picture him kind of
tall, good looking, you?
I don't know
- [Crow] A San Lorenzo
Milling Around Festival!
- [Joel] Hey GI Joe number one!
- [Tom] Hey mister my sister.
- Chocolate?
- Hey
- [Crow] Sorry about that Gary,
you gotta remember to duck boy.
- [Tom] What's the
matter muchachos?
Dad's trapped?
The rock canyon?
- Thank God
- Now ask 'em in Spanish
(speaks in foreign language)
- [Tom] Okay now
ask him in French.
Okay do German
again, I love this.
- I am Father Delgato.
- Arturo Ramos of
the University.
Dr Henry Scott from
the United States.
- I'm afraid I can't
introduce this one
- And the parents?
- [Crow] Don't give him
to me, I didn't do it.
- I think it might
be better if we
discussed this inside Father.
- [Crow] Batting practice.
(speaks in foreign language)
- Dead, they were dead.
And now Father do you
believe there's a demon bug
killing us all one by one?
I'll take Manuel.
I'll take him with me!
- [Crow] You know Gary
talked to me that way once.
Once.
- Gentlemen I know you are
weary after your journey.
Can I offer you good hospitality
the village may provide?
- [Joel] We tie you to a pole
and spank you with reeds.
- [Tom] The Milling
About Festival
continues well into the night.
Let's mill out of here.
- [Joel] Yeah let's mill.
- The look of death that none
of us had ever seen before.
(doors clank)
- Yee haw!
- All right as you guys
have probably noticed
most of the people in
this cast are from Mexico
and I thought it'd be nice
to take advantage of that
to have a little cross cultural
learning experience all right.
- Complete with subtitles?
- Right that's right,
Cambot you're gonna put the
subtitles up on the screen
interpreting the language
of our Southern brethren.
Now we're not that good at
it but we're trying to learn
and hey that's the most
important thing isn't it?
- We sure think so.
- That's right muchachos.
You want some refritos?
No I'm stuffed.
I'm good man.
- You don't know
what you're missing.
It's time to talk
about the film.
(speaks in foreign language)
- Never mind.
- Pass me a flour
tortilla will you?
- Are you sure you don't want
some green sauce with this?
- No I hate green.
(upbeat theme music)
- Tonight you will stay here
and maybe in the morning
things won't seem
quite so mysterious.
Indeed I hope so.
Here we are isolated almost
cut off from civilization.
Having lost family or friends,
is something absolutely unknown.
- [Joel] Still speaking
Spanish everybody?
Oui.
Si.
- Nyet.
- Lo.
Goodnight Father.
Goodnight.
- [Joel] They sure
headed off to bed early.
- [Crow] We missed dinner.
- [Tom] The Milling
Festival ends in chaos,
two angry villages slap
each other senseless
with large T bone steaks.
- I really appreciate it.
- [Tom] The spanking
it was great.
- See you later this afternoon
- Dr Ramos, Dr Scott, I
will ask you one more time
not to begin this
unnecessary expedition.
- [Crow] Look Frank
drop the cheesy accent.
- I don't see how we can be of
any further service to you.
- No I don't require
you for my work here.
- [Tom] It's more for pleasure.
- I only know that if
you start for that crater
and find yourself in
any kind of difficulties
men who are much more
badly needed here
will have to go find you.
- [Joel] Sorry Mr Selfish.
- That's why you must come
back safely and before sundown
with all the answers to
your questions and mine.
- [Crow] Amen to that Sluggo.
I mean Father Sluggo.
Padre.
Thank you.
- Now you've got me.
- [Tom] This looks like a
good place to put the boat in.
- We try around over
that side or over here?
- Neither one of them
looks exactly like a
Pan American highway.
- [Joel] Funny.
- Everyone's always said
that the best fissures
were on the Eastern slope.
You can see the lava there.
Maybe we can get close
enough to get some pictures
and plan our best approach.
- Just keep drinking.
- It's the Cisco kid!
- [Crow] Hey I can see another
movie through my binoculars.
- I don't know about that
but I found something
a lot more interesting.
- [Joel] Hey it's Dale Evans
and I thought she was stuffed.
- [Tom] Only mounted.
- Si señor, here have a look.
It'll do you a lot more good
than that bottle of water.
- [Joel] Again, he zung me.
- I don't see anything.
- Ah yes now I see him.
- Oh Doc you haven't
got that thing in focus.
- They're focused and
it's a very handsome horse
and I'd likely get started.
- [Joel] I know she's a
little plump but come on.
- There was a girl on
that horse, come on.
- [Tom] The horse
must've eaten her.
I think I see her.
- [Crow] Hey that's
the same place
they filmed Robot Monster.
- Now don't move too much.
I said don't move.
We'll find out if
you're all right first.
- [Joel] She's all
right and she'll be
perfect for our experiments.
- Except I could've done
this more gracefully
if I'd known
spectators were around.
- [Tom] Looked fine
from where I'm standing.
- Gently now.
- No broken bones señorita?
No sharp pain?
- No really I'm all right.
I've fallen off Lucero before.
Not for many years but I
really can ride gentlemen.
- Hank Scott.
Dr Arturo Ramos.
- Oh the luck of the Alvares.
Come off a horse and then
right next to a doctor.
- Doctors of Geology.
We operate only with
little hammers on rocks.
- [Joel] If you have kidney
stones we're the guys to call.
- Lucero always goes
back to Miraflores.
But the saddle, I don't know.
- I'll get it.
- You're very kind.
- [Crow] No he's
not, I'm kinder.
- Do you happen
to have a canteen?
- Well sure right
on the Jeep come on.
There's a mirror you can use.
- Great.
- We'll be here
several weeks at least.
See we're conducting.
- [Tom] Try a little of this.
I made it myself,
it's my own sweat
- You make it sound like a
very intriguing occupation.
- [Tom] Well I didn't mean to.
- It is, you meet such
interesting volcanoes.
- [Crow] And you're one of them.
- [Joel] What do you know.
Couple of rocks piled
on top of other rocks.
That's kind of fishy.
Let's dig down a
little bit and yeah.
What?
"Thou shalt not ki."
Huh.
I'll take that back.
Should make the saddle heavier.
- Hey Hank!
- [Joel] Look at this!
It says "Thou shalt not ki."
- Thank you doctor.
- [Joel] What do
you make of that?
- [Tom] I guess we're
not supposed to "Ki".
- I found this near the saddle.
- Oh is that good?
- I'll say it is, it's obsidian.
- [Crow] Oh I don't
think it's that bad.
- Well I wouldn't know.
Cattle yes but rocks.
Could I ask another
favor of you?
- [Joel] Can I
borrow some makeup?
- Would you mind turning back
and taking me to San Lorenzo?
- We'd be glad to.
- Thank you.
- [Crow] Wow you'll do
anything for a chick.
- I must get there today.
- [Tom] Where'd you get
your hat block Dale?
- Riders to help with my cattle.
That old volcano is really
causing a lot of
trouble this time.
- Yeah we heard in the
village about your cowboys.
- Oh?
Well if I lose my cattle
I lose everything.
How are things at Sal Lorenzo?
- [Crow] Well the
Milling Festival is over
ended in a weird steak fight.
Found a baby though,
gave it to a priest.
And that pretty much sums up
where we are in the movie.
- [Tom] The weather
started getting
rough the tiny ship was tossed.
- Is that any reason to act
like frightened children?
- I don't think it's just
a poisonous plant señorita.
Even in this climate
you don't grow them
that can push in the side of
a building and wreck a car.
- [Joel] Oh but we do.
You're not from
around here are you?
Strange man.
- [Crow] The Milling
Festival over the citizens
are loaded on to flatbed
trucks like so many cattle.
- [Tom] Everybody don't "ki!"
- Oh don't forget.
You promised to use Miraflores
as your headquarters.
- It will be a great
convenience señorita.
- Will it really?
- Right.
- [Joel] Hey Stevo
flip you for her.
- [Tom] Hey you see my haircut?
Look I got a haircut too!
Look haircut, haircut,
haircut, haircut, haircut.
We all got our haircut!
(speaks in foreign language)
All of you.
Let me ask you this.
- [Crow] Are those foam hats?
I told you to wear mouse ears.
- Would you have
become frightened
of sounds in the night and run
like silly children to
the safety of the village?
- Yeah, absolutely.
- I would.
- I say only this muchachos.
I've known you all
for all my life.
We've always worked together.
- [Joel] Me usually
bossing you around.
- That's right.
- If you don't wish to return
just to help me save my cattle
for me then, return
to save Miraflores.
(speaks in foreign language)
- [Joel] Looks like
the answer is no.
- Gracias.
- [Tom] All right señors
back to my house for tacos.
Hats on.
- Dr Scott, Mayor
Garcia wants to see you.
- Where is he?
- In the laboratory
with Dr De La Cruz.
- Laboratory?
- You'll be surprised by the
experiments that go on there.
- [Crow] He's making
a taco salad where
you can actually eat the bowl!
(upbeat theme music)
- Doctor is that the patrolman?
- Yes.
Sergeant Vega.
Relieved doing his duty now
who may perform a greater one.
- [Tom] Ick.
- [Joel] You see I deep fried
a small portion of soft shell
now look at the salsa
I mixed up here.
- [Tom] They are flavor buds,
they are bursting with flavor!
- Well?
- Black subcutaneous cells that
had just burst or run rampant.
- [Crow] So that salsa is
really really hot then right?
- Not from any poison I can
identify with this equipment
Lopez you help again please?
- [Joel] Isn't that the
guy from The Eurythmics?
- In this pure alcohol
and this distilled water
and this tequila.
- [Tom] Ah that's for me.
- And this water with some salt.
- [Crow] And then
bring some Shinola
and we'll compare it with
the last one I gave you.
- Think it is a poison then?
- I do.
- Not a chemical poison Doctor?
- No.
But I believe for many reasons.
- [Joel] More like a paste
like I use in my hair.
- I have had a little
experience with them.
The venoms of the snakes.
The wasps and spiders.
But I will prepare the
slides and the specimens
and take them to a
man in Mexico City
who will be sure to know.
- [Crow] Now do you
serve those with crackers
or do you spread them on
those toasted garlic rounds?
- Well as you say if
it's an organic poison
anything from nature the Great
Vilasko will identify it.
- [Tom] The Great Vilasko,
juggler sword swallower
and pathologist extraordinaire.
- One wound here with no blood.
Then the situation
of the tissues.
The strange bacteria.
Bacteria I think found
in the soil samples
near the footprints.
Footprints?
- [Crow] What prints?
- Footprints.
- Footprints?
- Where something
knocks down dwellings,
flattens cornfields.
- [Crow] Now these
aren't actual footprints
this is feta cheese
but it smells like feet
and that's as close
as we could get.
- Whatever it is my friends
I don't believe anyone
has ever seen a foot,
a claw, this size
except those poor unfortunates
who wish they never had.
- One question Doctor.
- What?
- I hope I can answer it.
- The alcohol, the
distilled water,
the salt solution, I
can understand that.
- [Joel] It all makes a great
salad dressing doesn't it.
- Well in your country I believe
you call it a coffee break.
- [Crow] Hey let's
all grab a margarita
and head out to my turtle
pool what do you say?
- [Joel] Hey it's the big valley
and there's Barbara Stanwick.
- [Crow] There goes the
surrey with the fringe on top.
- [Tom] Don't forget the Alamo!
No wait, we can do better.
Davey Crocker is a dork!
No.
Remember the, oh forget it.
- Looks like you
were pretty lucky.
That thing really
came close didn't it?
- [Crow] Yeah it
used to be worse.
- We were blessed that
it didn't go any further
our plantation
would've been ruined
like the rest of the land.
- [Joel] Makes a lot of sense.
- [Tom] Meanwhile back at
Neighborville Illinois.
- Señorita thank
heavens you're safe.
- [Joel] Oh really?
I was worried about you.
- I began to search the hills.
- Oh Peo I had already
been found by someone else.
This is Dr Scott and Dr Ramos.
This is my foreman Peo.
- Hi Peo.
- [Crow] Chump.
- Not only comfortable
but cool too.
- Yes sometimes I
think being cool
is by far the most
important on days like this.
Well I know you'll want showers.
- [Joel] Wow it looks like
she lives at the Gala winery.
- Florentina.
Show Dr Ramos to the blue room?
- [Crow] And then sponge
bathe our guests won't you?
- Show Dr Scott
to the left wing.
- I'll take care of them!
- Well I'll see you later
and you can tell me all
about your expedition.
- [Tom] You mean in the shower?
- Not bad doc.
- [Tom] Meanwhile in the shower.
(cows moo)
- Good day's work.
- Chalaco not bad.
- [Joel] All right
everybody thank you
but Oklahoma has
been cast already.
- By Thursday.
Why put on such a face?
We will do it if I have
to stay in the saddle
without sleep myself.
- You must understand
can't you see?
The cattle knows that something
evil is carried on the wind.
- [Crow] That's the cat.
- Now let us have a good supper
and forgot these superstitions.
- [Joel] Hey quit
shouting back there!
Hey cut it out!
- [Tom] Meanwhile
back at the dog.
- Would you like
some brandy sir?
- [Crow] Brandy for a dog?
- Just a minute.
Juanito hurry with the brandy.
Would you like some too?
- Please.
- [Juanito] I'll
take care of them.
- Muchas Gracias.
- [Joel] Take a shot for
yourself little buddy.
- [Tom] Kid's kind
of a kissup isn't he?
- [Crow] Jerry Mathers
has to be virile.
- Can I make a complaint Teresa?
- Oh I'm sorry what
was not done suitably?
- [Joel] Oh the dog
was a little well done.
- Everything was
done beautifully.
You know you're making
it very difficult
to think about
settling down to work.
- Well is that so bad?
- That all depends.
Might be very bad if I stop
thinking about work altogether
and just started
concentrating on pleasure.
- Hank those volcanoes have
been there for hundreds of years
I'm sure they wouldn't mind
waiting just a little longer.
- [Tom] What are they
talking about Joel?
- [Joel] Sexual healing?
- I've got something
to show you.
- [Crow] Let me put my new
Leonard Nimoy album on,
the Sings The Ballad
of Bilbo Baggins.
- I noticed it last
night at the village.
- [Joel] Looks like
a decoupage Hummel.
- See anything?
Hold it up against the light.
- [Joel] Looks like
Wisconsin delve.
- That's fantastic Doc.
- Thank you.
- [Theresa] There's a
scorpion trapped in there.
- [Crow] You are bold
and assertive and
you get along well with Libras.
- I wanted to show it to
you before I broke it open.
- [Tom] Not on the table
I just had it re felted.
(scorpion screeches)
- Alive!
Impossible!
- It's a prehistoric
crunchy treat.
- I can't believe it life
enduring for centuries like
this and under all that heat?
- [Tom] My underwear drawer?
- [Crow] Hey I hope you
know you voided the warranty
when you cracked it open pal.
- [Joel] I think
I'll name him Buster.
- [Tom] It's an ancient
squeaking scorpion.
- Pardon me señores do you
like to keep scorpions?
I know a place where
there are millions!
- [Hank] Not like
this one Juanito.
- [Tom] This one squeaks.
- Pancho!
- Cisco!
- You don't know how to behave?
I have to send you out.
- I want a magnifying glass
to watch this little monster.
- [Joel] You mean
the little kid?
- You know I could throw
this scorpion out the window
and then we'd really be alone.
- [Tom] Well except
the dog, the cook,
the small boy and your friend.
- Why don't we?
(phone rings)
- Oh excuse me!
The line's been fixed.
- [Crow] Is that a problem?
- Hello.
Hello?
- [Tom] I'm a lineman
for the county
and I drive the main road.
- Oh is the line all fixed?
- All clear ma'am.
Miraflores is the
last one señora.
- [Crow] And now ladies and
gentlemen the star of our show.
It's the roaches!
- [Tom] Works every time.
Ew he's leaking look at that.
(screams)
- [Crow] Let's see
what am I hungry for.
Lobster yeah, that's
what I wanted.
(dramatic music)
- Oh hi Crusty.
- Hi lady fish.
- What?
- [Tom] No what's on first.
- [Joel] What a time
to be stuck up a pole.
- [Tom] Once you've tasted
linemen you'll never go back.
I bet you can't eat just one.
- Hank come here!
- [Tom] The line's been bugged!
- Listen to this.
- Hello, hello!
Hello, what's wrong?
- [Lineman] Look out!
- [Joel] Could you
scream a little slower?
I can't understand you.
- Run!
- [Crow] Roughly
translated he's saying
"This would not have happened
"had we installed fiber optics"
- [Tom] I think I
can take that thing.
(speaks in foreign language)
- [Tom] Sunday Sunday Sunday!
We turn the floor of the Sonora
desert into a giant blood pit.
It's machine meets arachnid
in one on one action.
Gogo the gorilla and
all time powerful
meister Big Scorp.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Hm delicious
guy on a stick.
- [Joel] You got a little.
(screams)
- [Crow] The neat treat
that's fun to eat.
- [Joel] This might sting a bit.
No it's gonna sting
a lot, definitely.
- Where's the Arroyo Bridge?
- I'll show you.
- In Arroyo.
- Pancho what is
happening to you tonight?
- [Crow] I gotta do a
film with Jim Belushi.
- Doc we have to go over to the
bridge there's some trouble!
Come on.
- You be a good boy.
(barks)
Bad dog bad dog!
- [Crow] Come back,
come back Rin Tin Tin!
(barks)
- [Joel] Look kid the dog
obviously doesn't like you.
- [Tom] Dogs love the rich
taste of gigantic scorpion.
- Señorita!
- [Tom] Shouldn't we
unhook the boat first?
- I cannot say!
- Help Mr Hank!
- Well that's Juanito!
- [Joel] Juanito,
who's gonna save a kid
named after a snack cracker?
(dramatic music)
- [Hank] Run Juanito!
- [Tom] Not that way!
- Call for help.
- [Crow] Don't shoot the
boy, shoot the monster!
I'm getting scared!
- [Joel] Mrs Butterworth help!
- Where is Juanito?
- He's safe!
Operator!
(upbeat theme music)
- But I just don't
understand it at all.
- Well we'll go through it
again one more time okay?
At approximately the
same time every day
Joel goes into his cabin
stretches out horizontally on
his bunk and closes his eyes.
- Yeah and then he holds
perfectly still and shuts down.
- No except it's not
a complete shutdown
because every now and
then he rolls over
and he'll say things
like "Oh no Mr French
"puppy didn't hide the cat!"
- Or or one time I heard him
yell "Don't stop, don't stop!"
- Gypsy we're busy here.
That's not the weird
part, it's really not.
He'll get up he'll walk into a
little closet and
he makes water.
- Yeah and what
does he do with it?
He flushes it out into space.
Go figure.
- It'd be like if we were
to just drain hydro fluid
to jettison it into space.
- Yeah.
(howls)
- Oh cute girl go take a powder.
- Okay here's a paradox for you,
he's programmed to grow
hair on his face right?
But every time he gets up
from his bunk he cuts it off!
- Yeah right and
then it grows back
again the next day,
what does he do?
- He cuts it off again.
- Yeah this is one of these
logically strange loops.
Some sort of bizarre
non euclidian
human projection pattern
which makes no sense.
(howls)
- [Tom] Owie owie owie!
- Oh I tell you
buddy human nature
is a hard thing to figure.
(alarm blares)
Oh we got movies on, let's go!
(doors clank)
- [Joel] Tom why'd
you break Gypsy?
- [Tom] She tried
to consume me Joel.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- [Crow] This is the operator.
I'm not in right now.
Nothing important is
happening so I left.
This is a recording.
- Oh!
- Ah!
- [Crow] Here comes the grand
finale I love this part.
- [Tom] Oh this is
your landlord calling.
I'm sorry but you
won't be getting
your damage deposit back.
- [Crow] Come on everybody
it's just a big bug!
Ain't you ever seen
a big bug before?
Come on nothing to worry.
Whoa what the?
Gary get out of my way!
- [Tom] It's crazy day!
We're slashing and
bashing prices!
Yes that's right all giant
scorpions get in free!
Free hot dogs and
balloons for the kids!
Hey come on down and visit me
code jail I'm in code prison.
Get me out, get me out, come on.
Come on down to crazy
day this Sunday.
- [Crow] Oh I saw
that in Potemkin once.
- [Tom] It's the
Wahaca step sequence.
- [Joel] These soccer games
really can get out of hand.
- [Crow] You're not
supposed to use your hands.
Hey get me!
I'm stinging peasants!
- [Joel] I hate to tell you this
that's not how you use the gun.
It's upside down.
- [Tom] It's udder chaos!
Cows.
Cow could I say that?
- It must be after the cattle.
- [Crow] Well just rope
and throw and brand them,
don't try to understand them.
- [Joel] Oh you got a little uh.
- [Tom] I told you kids
no horseplay in the house.
- [Joel] You got a
little, yeah eugh.
- Come on!
- [Joel] Man I wonder if that
thing can plow a driveway.
It should be great.
- [Crow] I don't think it can,
doesn't have the
right attachments.
- [Tom] Flint Michigan.
On a clear day you
can see the GM plant
on the outskirts of town.
Hey and look there's
Michael Moore.
- [Crow] I'm telling you Brad
I'm gonna get to
Mecina before Monty.
- [Joel] MASH 4077
best care anywhere.
- [Tom] It's Sydney Freeman.
- Dr Vilasko.
- [Crow] Hey Hawkeye didn't
recognize you in the civvies.
- This is fantastic.
- [Joel] Oh you like it?
Thanks!
- Thank God Father we
thought you were all dead.
- [Tom] Just part of me.
- This is all that remains.
Even the animals.
I cannot speak of this night.
- [Tom] Well then just
don't speak of it.
- Father I have been
sent here in charge
of emergency arrangements.
All that are left will
be moved to safety.
Please tell everyone to be
ready to leave San Lorenzo.
And Father they
may only take what
they can carry in their arms.
- [Tom] I'm not your father.
- Where is the laboratory?
- Over there.
- [Crow] Is it
lavatory or Laboratory?
- As soon as I
received the samples
I identified the poison
is that of a scorpion.
But I had no concept of the
creature's size
until I saw this.
- [Joel] Your feta cheese?
- This specimen
found by Dr Ramos
is of a species thought to be
extinct as a Tri Asian Era.
- [Tom] As a what?
- We have known it in a
passive state but never alive.
Now from the bowels of the Earth
it has come forth again
to plague the Earth.
- What can we do?
I emptied the machine
gun on one of them.
- I beg of you all
not to lose your head.
- [Joel] Have you tried
reasoning to them?
- We have a few advantages
against this enemy.
- [Tom] First we're
small, we can run fast.
- Thus we have
the daylight hours
to try to find and destroy them.
Secondly they're somewhat
slow and lethargic.
- [Crow] And we have
giant 40 foot pinchers.
No wait that's the scorpions.
- One question sir.
- Yes?
- What weapon to do
you intend to use?
- Gas.
- [Tom] We're in Mexico
that should be easy to find.
- It has been proved effective
against normal species
let us pray it works against.
- [Tom] Enormous pieces?
- If it does not?
- [Crow] We give up and die.
- May God help all of you.
- [Tom] Or some of you.
Like you.
- [Joel] Okay Milling
Festival's over,
it's the Big Hat Fest.
- I want to do what I can too.
- Señorita Alvares I
understand your emotions.
- Believe me Dr Vilasko I'm
not trying to be emotional.
I wouldn't ask to come along
if I thought I couldn't help.
- Teresa you don't
know the hardships.
- Dr Vilasko, Major Cocio,
I know this area like
the palm of my hand.
- [Tom] But she can't ride
a horse to save her life.
- I'm a good shot.
You said yourself you needed
all the help you could get.
- Señorita Alvares, I think
you have found yourself a job.
- [Crow] The pay's rotten
but the hours stink.
- Major Cocio and I
are planning this.
- [Joel] See I got
this lake property
and it goes all the
way back to the woods.
- I want to go with you.
I want to do a job.
- Don't worry Juanito,
we'll get together again.
That's a promise.
See if you can find my
boots for me will you?
- I know where they are!
- [Crow] Oh they stink.
Hey did you actually
pay for these?
- [Joel] Line please.
- Here they are.
- Oh good!
- [Crow] Now stop eyeballing
them kid and give them to me.
- Kinda like those huh?
Tell you what Juanito when
you get to be a big man
I'll get you a pair
just like these.
- [Joel] No thanks.
- Thank you Mr Hank!
- You like that huh?
- I know how to ride very good.
I know how to shoot very good.
- [Crow] Yeah yeah
we know you're
superboy too bad you can't act.
Hey can I call you Gary?
- Ah Juanito.
You know sometimes
even a half a man
has a lot of
different jobs to do.
And right now the most
important job for you to do
is to take care of
your grandmother.
- She can take care of herself!
- [Tom] Off her Juan
you'll be paid well for it.
- You've got plenty of time
to do more exciting things.
- And you?
You be very careful and
don't get hurt won't you?
- [Tom] You work on your diction
I'll catch up with you later.
- [Joel] Yeah that's
what Shane said.
- Okay.
- [Tom] Here they
are the 15th fairway.
Boy I wish they'd keep those
horses away from the green.
- I don't see a thing Dr
Vilasko, might as well go on.
- All right.
- [Crow] You playing the
Top Flight Five aren't you?
I usually use range balls
out here in the rough.
- [Joel] They're playing
the volcano hole.
Next is the windmill
and that's really tough.
- [Tom] Looks like he's gonna
use an iron on this one.
A little hard to believe
but he's been having
a lot of trouble with
his driver and his woods.
Looks like he's going
for a tough par.
Hey he was in our
foursome last week!
This is a rough hole.
- Major.
- Yes Doctor?
- Tell your captain
to hold all the
heavy equipment
until we call for it.
- [Tom] You mean the irons?
- Look at this!
A great big opening!
- [Joel] Here's
the pit everybody!
- [Crow] Wow it is tough.
He's got to four
caddy that hole.
- Look there's something
wrong with his horse!
He's falling in!
- [Joel] No actors
were abused in the
making of this motion picture.
- [Crow] That's gonna
cost them a stroke
- [Tom] Take a full swing!
- We must get down
to the lower level.
- [Crow] The lady's tee?
(dramatic music)
Okay who has the orange ball?
- [Joel] Hey they moved the pin!
- This crevice is new.
It must've opened during
one of the earthquakes.
This looks like
a job for us Doc.
- Of course.
- No transport?
How deep do you say it is?
- Well Doc and I've
been down many a cave
but there's no way
of really telling.
- [Joel] I think it cuts
down into the right,
we should be able to bogey it.
Hey cut it out!
Ouch!
- Well the only
way we can find out
is try to go down
there ourselves.
What do you say Doc?
- [Joel] What are you high?
- Would that poisonous gas
work in a crevice this big?
- I could not anticipate
such a void as this.
- [Joel] I'm not a
big enough crevice.
- Major I think you better bring
all your heavy
equipment up here.
Crane tanks and all.
- Captain bring the crane
and all the heavy equipment.
You want my men
to go down there?
It is suicide.
- Don't worry about it.
Doc and I haven't had a decent
elevator ride in a long time.
- [Tom] We commit
suicide every day.
Got my snowmobile here.
Sno Cat really a beauty.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm a stowaway!
- [Joel] No you're
a volunteer kid.
- Do me a favor will you?
And just stay out of the way.
- Yes Mr Hank.
- Good.
And just sit in the Jeep
like a big boy okay?
- [Joel] Yeah wear that
checkerboard bib overalls
and hold a big sloppy
hamburger like that.
- Why the birds professor?
- Because if the
birds stop singing
that means there's
poison gas in the cave.
- [Crow] Fine time
to go jousting.
- Neither of you, it's
not your responsibility.
- Who's responsibility is it?
- [All] The producers.
- The army.
The people who live here!
- Now look Doc and I
know more about caves
than anyone else here.
- [Tom] Give me my gum back.
Thank you.
- [Joel] No you got it.
Here I want you to have it.
- Why did you do that?
- Maybe I just wanted
to see what you'd do?
- What did I do?
- [Crow] Well I don't
know but you did it first.
- Señorita.
You can help us if you will
keep the log of the descent.
How many meters down, the
reports which are made.
- Sure, keep yourself
busy, that's my theory.
Oh don't forget take
care of little Juanito.
- [Joel] Juanito?
Oh you mean my kid!
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] And so
we enter the cage
knowing the Earth's fiercest
creatures await us below.
Zsa Zsa.
- [Joel] He said down.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Lower and
lower we go traveling
past the matte paintings.
- [Tom] We suffer from the
banes of nitrogen narcosis.
- [Joel] I think
we're gonna need
a lot bigger boat you guys.
- [Crow] Should I get the cops?
I'll get the cops.
- Look down there.
- [Tom] Hello stop cage!
Big crab!
Big guy!
Oh boy!
Bring us up!
Stop the cage!
- [Crow] Send down a
little lemon butter.
- Hold on a second.
- [Joel] Hal why don't
you go down there
and stand next to the creature
so I can get a sense of scale?
- Okay I got a picture of it.
Lower on.
- All right lower them down.
- [Tom] Down did I say down?
Up, I meant up.
He's gonna clip that
line like a nose hair.
- [Joel] Hey look over there
it says Arnie Sacknessen.
- [Crow] Deeper
and deeper we went
until our little thread was
all the way down you know.
- A huge cavern, I've never
seen a cave so big in my life.
- Can you see the
signs of Mendoza?
- No not from here.
We'll take a look around.
- [Joel] Seems like
a nice enough place.
- [Tom] At first.
- [Crow] We step
to see if it's cold
and lifeless when actually
it is teeming with life.
Here we see a sea anemone.
It's seemingly fragile structure
adapted to the
massive pressures.
At this depth the sea pressure
could crush a man's
head like a pimple.
- [Joel] Hey Chirpy.
- [Tom] Is this Dune?
- [Crow] Here we see
one of the beautiful
creatures of the sea floor.
Though it appears vicious to
the eye it is very docile.
You can see the creature's lure
which is a lump of flesh
in front of the ink sack.
- [Joel] Well this
is the winner of
the Uniroyal Pioneer Trophy.
Now this float is called
The Little Inchworm.
It's made entirely out of
white coral flowers
and dried shellfish.
It's a real piece of work.
Kathy Lee?
- Hank answer!
- [Crow] Hey he
likes to wear hats.
We just find a bug that can wear
this hat and we've got our man.
- Or their worm.
- Exactly.
- Are you there Hank?
Dr Ramos.
- [Tom] Elven boy hid
behind the gas tanks.
- Hello, hello?
- Hello!
- Damn these Sprint lines!
- Yes?
- Mendoza's dead.
- We just saw a
worm 30 feet long.
- [Crow] And boy
does it catch fish.
- We want to look around
a little more first.
- Hey Doc!
- Over here!
- [Tom] There's a
big set over here!
Over here, over here.
- [Joel] Stay down Sabu.
Aw yuck, look out.
♪ The ants go marching
one by one hurrah hurrah ♪
- There must be
a nest somewhere.
♪ The ants go
marching one by one ♪
♪ The humans stopped
to shoot a gun ♪
- Doesn't even penetrate it.
- Try another one.
- [Crow] Better call Orkin.
Or throw the boy at them.
- [Joel] Yep these are
scorpion prints all right.
- [Tom] Are they in the
basement of the volcano,
is that the deal?
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Made him
mad, not a good thing.
- [Joel] You know even
if they catch that thing.
they're gonna need a lemon
the size of a Volvo to eat it.
- [Crow] I think I'll go
make some yummy curry sauce.
With my own body.
- [Tom] Becky?
Engine Joe?
Huck?
- [Joel] Let's knock
off for the day Bill.
It's been a long one and I sure
could go for a nice cold brew.
Scorpions like this always keep
lots of ice cold beer around.
- [Crow] Sounds like there's
an opera going on next door.
- [Joel] I got 20
bucks that says the
scorpion who wins this one.
- [Tom] I'm just
plain terrified.
(screeches)
Well he's got a foreign object.
Well Carmel I can't believe
what I'm seeing here.
- [Crow] What does it smell
like in here to you guys?
(screeches)
- Yuck.
- Growdy.
- Must be the
grandaddy of them all
- [Crow] Wilford Brimley?
- [Joel] Good make sure they
can see us, thanks a lot.
- That's how they
kill each other,
that weak spot in the throat.
- [Tom] Good eye.
- [Crow] Go out there and
strangle them will you Hal?
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Oh great
it's a wood tick.
He's gonna get
Lyme's disease now!
- [Crow] Quick get
a lit cigarette!
- Help!
Help!
- [Joel] That doesn't sound
like a giant mutated scorpion.
- [Tom] Come on afraid
of a little tick?
You little pansy.
- Help!
Help!
- [Tom] Juanito come back!
(upbeat theme music)
- [Hank] Stay back
in the cave Juanito!
- [Crow] Because you got
some explaining to do boy.
- [Joel] Let's get some Deep
Woods OFF and finish him off.
- I thought I told you
to stay in the Jeep.
what are you doing down here?
- I came to help you.
- You knucklehead.
- To help us?
No come on.
- [Tom] All right
you're bait come on.
Holy buckets.
- Mr Hank, Mr Hank!
Look!
- [Joel] Oh well
this isn't good.
Not at all.
I mean I've seen good before
and it didn't look
anything this.
Remember that bad thing we saw?
Well it looked
like this remember?
Definitely bad.
- [Tom] That scorpion really
wants to use that phone booth.
- [Crow] Okay play
him out a little.
Keep your rocked hip high.
And when you're
ready set the hook.
- The crane will be pulled in!
- Throw some rocks
under that crane!
- [Tom] No you do it.
- There goes our cage,
gas tanks, everything.
- [Joel] And my
lunch was in there!
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Come here you!
- [Joel] Yuck.
- [Crow] Great we lost 'em.
He went under the boat,
now we're out of bait
- Here take the cable Doc,
and send it back out
as fast as we can.
- Bring it in slow.
- Maybe they're on it?
- Oh pull it up.
Please pull it up!
- Keep bringing it in.
- [Joel] Just keep thinking
about your happy thoughts,
don't look down.
I know you're a bendy
doll in this scene.
Don't give up.
- Come on, hold on!
- [Tom] I bet you
couldn't even climb
the rope in high
school could you?
You gutless wonder, you wimp!
Get me I'm a bendy doll.
Higher and higher he goes.
He's getting a nosebleed.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Well how was it?
- [Crow] By this time my
lungs were aching for air.
- What happened to Hank?
- Hank and Juanito
are down there too.
Get a loop on the cable
send it down quick!
- Make a loop on the cable!
- [Joel] Loopy on the cable.
(dramatic music)
Okay now get a shot
of me with the buck.
Make a real good pose there.
- [Crow] Oh I'll send the rope
back down for you I promise.
By the way can I have your bike?
- [Tom] Great he's
a human piñata now.
Darn darn darn!
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Grab a Mountain Dew
and try that, it's a blast.
- Oh Juanito.
Oh Juanito why did you do it?
- [Tom] We are engaged.
- It'll be dark in about an hour
and those scorpions will
be coming out again.
- You couldn't use the gas?
- No we lost it in
the molten lava.
There must be about 50 of
those things down there.
- Can't we close that opening
with dynamite and seal it?
- You have no idea as to
the size of that place.
Wait until you see
these pictures.
- [Crow] They're great,
remember corn palace last year?
Even better than that!
Oops I left the lens cap on.
- Major we must try to seal
it shut with an explosion.
We must start before nightfall.
- [Tom] Okay.
- [Crow] So there was a
hook on the door handle.
Scary.
- The giants don't
last that long.
They eat their own weight
every three or four days.
- But suppose they
find another way,
those passages down there.
- [Tom] They're crafty.
- [Joel] They did play
a cruise ship once
when I was a kid
but other than that.
Major.
Yes Doctor?
- Let's close it.
Ready?
- Aim.
- Let her go.
(explosion booms)
- I guess that does it.
- Wanna bet?
- [Joel] It seemed
like a good idea.
At first.
- [Crow] Hey your
apartment is great.
- This isn't the end of
anything, not for us.
It's the beginning.
- Hank all of us have
done our work now and
thank heaven it can be done
without any more tragedy.
And you still have your survey
of the volcanoes to make yet.
- [Joel] By the way you're
sitting on a hornets' nest.
- I'll be home every
night for dinner.
- I have to leave at once.
I should've left for the
States two months ago
to buy a cattle for the herd.
- [Tom] Did you leave
the water running?
- You'll be in Mexico
City for a week first huh?
- [Joel] Very powerful woman.
- I'll finish up my work with
Doc and I'll meet you there
and you can show me the town.
- [Crow] Well at the
city of 8 billion people.
You better go talk to
the chamber of commerce.
- A day, two days?
I don't want to settle
for just two days Hank.
- I don't want just
two days either.
- [Tom] I want five days.
Five nights, double
occupancy, air fare included!
- I don't want them
to fool me either.
- I'm not gonna.
I like you very much indeed
and I want you very much.
- [Tom] Your breath
is like mummy meat.
- [Crow] Cookie.
- [Joel] Meanwhile
at Hawaii 5 0.
- [Hank] Dr Scott!
Hello I can hardly hear you.
- This is Dr Vilasko.
- Oh Dr Vilasko,
how are you sir?
- [Crow] Well I'm tying
some details yeah.
Yeah it's perp's day
down here you know?
- Hank I regret to have
to complicate the plans
you and Dr Ramos
have made for so long
but some of my colleagues
here in Mexico are very
very anxious to talk
to you both at once.
- I don't really think
there's anything we can add
to what you already
know Dr Vilasko.
- I am with the Director
of Civilian Defense
and High Army Officers
right now Hank.
- [Tom] That's great.
- It is imperative that you both
return here at once to
complete your report.
I don't like to say.
- [Tom] What kind of
salary are we talking here?
- Everything is under
control isn't it?
- There's no cause
for alarm not at all.
But a request for cooperation
has been required by.
By a good neighbor of the South.
- [Tom] Noriega?
Daniel Ortega?
Tio Sancho?
- Already postponed
the trip five times.
I guess once more won't matter.
What?
A plane?
Yeah sure that would help a lot.
- [Joel] How do you
planning on flying?
- Dr Vilasko do you
suppose there'd be room
for three on that plane?
- Of course there'll
be room for three.
- All right.
Yes sir I understand.
Right see you then.
Hasta luego.
- [Tom] He bought it!
Everyone hide behind
the furniture.
- I don't think so.
He assumes that the
danger is completely over.
- That's fine.
- You seemed very willing to
postpone our trip once you
learned that Teresa could
ride with us on the plane.
- Well at least it was
some sort of an inducement.
- My friend remember
this is not the balcony
of the neighborhood
movie theater.
- [Tom] Although the
floor's just as sticky.
- And when a man shows as much
attention to a girl as you have
all of a sudden
he's in a cathedral
and wondering how he got there.
- So what do you got
against marriage Doc?
- I try to remember what my
father told me at one time.
He said "Arturo every time".
- [Crow] Hey come on yo what
are you Gabe Caplin here?
What's with the story?
Hey get on with it.
Is this a Bob Newhart bit?
- [Joel] Right I'll
get the sedatives.
It's Benito Mussolini.
- [Crow] Hey I see
your hair plugs took
- Dr Vilasko has asked me
to take you to him at once.
- Right away.
- [Joel] I don't think
your hat's quite dead yet.
- I have order to take the
señorita Alvarez
wherever she wishes.
You gentlemen must then
accompany me to the university.
- All right.
- [Crow] We better
get out of here.
- [Tom] Let's go.
- [Crow] Follow me.
- [Tom] Look it's
the Kaluha factory.
(doors clank)
Hey everybody, my name is Joel.
Welcome to the Satellite
of Love today we have.
- [Crow] I think
his voice is a bit
higher Servo more like this.
Hey sirs what's the
experiment for this week?
- [Tom] That's pretty
good but he tends
to roll his R's a little bit.
More like this.
- [Joel] Hey what are
you guys up to anyway?
- [Crow] Wow that's perfect
that sounds just like him.
- [Tom] Ixnay Crow.
Ixnay on the Oeljay.
- What?
Oh right sorry.
- We were just doing our
little tribute to the genius
behind the character
effects in this film.
- Yeah that black scorpion is
terrific, it's very realistic.
- And you know who the creator
of the stop action animation
was the one and
only Willis O'Brien.
- Oh we thought it
was Ray Harryhousen.
- That's a good
guess but actually
the great grandaddy of them
all was Willis O'Brien.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
He started the whole
thing actually.
He's the guy who
brought to the screen
such great science
fiction characters as
King Kong and Mighty Joe Young.
- Well didn't he also do a
bunch of those dinosaur movies?
- Right.
- He did something
like Valley of the?
- Valley of the Mist, that's
right and you'll be surprised
to know that a very young
stop animation animator
was on the scene just
learning from Willis O'Brien
and that man was
Ray Harryhousen.
And he also worked
on Mighty Joe Young.
- Oh so that's why
we're confused.
- That's right but you guys
did a great job on this model.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Hey Cambot bring
it in a little bit.
it's almost time to go
to commercials sign.
We'll be back everybody,
right after commercial sign.
(upbeat theme music)
- Now gentlemen.
- [Joel] Now that was a
cute little model I think.
- [Tom] Yeah it was
pretty cool I thought.
I wqorked all night on that.
- Almost directly
across from the fissure
where you and Dr
Scott descended.
You will see here
is the fissure.
This is San Lorenzo.
- [Tom] On the
Isle of Langerhans.
- Exactly here that the
photograph was taken.
- Gentlemen I still
think you're making
a mountain out of a molehill.
- [Joel] Actually
it's a volcano.
- You noticed how that mountain
went when we blew it up.
Nothing could live under
those tons of rock.
- Not if they were
under the rocks no.
- I don't think I
quite follow you.
- From your description
that Dr Vilasko told us
it is obvious that the cavern
in which you two men descended
is part of Jamilpa Caves.
Huge tunnels that
run under the Earth
at depths up to five miles.
- [Crow] Where we could
live so that the animals
could be bred and slaughtered!
- Some are flooded, part
of the underground lakes.
- [Tom] Look at that,
he's sporting a girdle.
- Here they are.
- [Tom] Check it out look.
- Notice how this large
fissure here is directly above
this arm of the system.
- [Tom] Which is
slightly swollen due
to the pressure on
the naughty bits.
- Is exactly the place where
you took your photographs.
- [Tom] Here on
the seventh green.
- Also notice that
here where the scorpion
was photographed from the air
is also part of the
connecting system.
The scorpions could easily
have fled underground
to one of many
underground shelters.
- [Joel] Is this
gonna be on the final?
- What is that long arm there?
- That is the cavern
which extends southward
to within 20 miles
of Mexico City.
There where it lies
under the railroad.
- [Tom] It's Walt
Disney and friends.
- [Crow] And Adolf Menjou.
- And when will they decide to
come to the surface after blop.
- [All] After Bob?
- So that is why we
brought you here.
Today after tomorrow
we want you to address
a group of scientific
and military experts
so that we may plan
for any emergency.
- [Tom] And we
enjoy your company
What kind of rifles
were you using?
How powerful?
- Well the cartridges
I was using
are supposed to penetrate
two inches of steel.
- [Joel] But then I'm flying.
- How do they kill each other?
- The throat, there's
a small part right here
that has no armor,
that's its weak point.
- When they attack
each other of course,
they have the poison to inject
into their enemy's throat.
- Can you duplicate the poison?
- No, not without
a giant scorpion.
- What we need is something
that'll penetrate that
small area exactly and then
send some sort of poison
into the circulatory systems.
What it could be I have no idea.
- [Tom] We'll deploy a
small throat lozenge.
- But with the meeting on Friday
I'm sure we will
reach a solution.
Gentlemen I do not
have to tell you
that everything we discuss
here is absolutely secret.
This city has 4 million people!
- [Crow] I'm gonna tell.
- If word of this leaks out
the panic of the population
would be worse
than the scorpions.
- [Crow] He's got the
pi sign on his head.
- [Tom] Meanwhile
at the Stork Club.
I think I'll have
the Bull, you honey?
- Nice dress, nice girl.
Well thank you.
Oh you mean me.
- I'm glad you can see
me in something else
besides those clothes
I wear at the ranch.
- [Joel] You mean that
woodchuck costume?
- Hank what's the
meeting on Friday about?
- Some geophysical contest
Dr Vilasko roped us in on.
Cigarette?
- Not right now.
- [Tom] Yes it is
- After you finish that where
am I taking you for dinner?
- [Tom] How about the IHOP?
- It's only 9:00.
- That's what I mean.
- Do you realize
this is Mexico City
and no one has dinner before
11:00 o'clock at night?
- [Tom] So then it should
be easy to get a table.
- Why it's practically
afternoon right now.
- [Joel] What are you on Dr
Seuss time all of a sudden?
- Oh am I going to
have trouble with you.
- Well you work on it teacher.
I think you could solve me.
- [Joel] Hey look at me I'm a
Rubik's Cube all of a sudden!
Whoa!
- [Tom] Meanwhile at the
Toboggan room at the IHOP.
- [Crow] Another waffle my dear?
Another short
stack for table 12!
- Aren't you overdoing
it a bit Hank?
- [Joel] No these waffles go
right to my head, I'm in love.
- What's the matter
don't you like caviar?
- Oh I love it.
- [Tom] But not on my pancakes.
- I could never understand
why it's so expensive.
- Well it's a full year's
work for a sturgeon.
- That guy!
- He's a card.
- [Tom] He's a regular fish egg.
- [Joel] He gets
all the good ones.
- [Crow] Yeah should
I be going to bed
or going to work or getting up?
- [Tom] There's water coming
out of his neck, look at that.
- I wish you'd change your mind.
You don't have to go away
and that volcano can wait.
- No.
You'll get through with your
speech tomorrow and your
silly expedition and I'll do
everything I have to do and
then when we come back we won't
have a worry in the world.
(horn blows)
- [Joel] Yeah except
he'll make me look
at his model train
all night probably.
- [Tom] Hey crusty
scorpions here,
get your big crusty scorpions.
- [Crow] I was afraid of this.
Scorpion hobos.
Putting pesos on the tracks
to see if they flatten.
- [Joel] Hey Crusty
what's your sign?
Just kidding.
(horn blows)
- [Tom] I think I can, I
think I can, I think I can.
- [Joel] Yuck.
- [Tom] What's worse.
Hey get me I'm messing
up time tables whoa!
He's gonna play
chicken with the train.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Wow I
shouldn't have had all
that tequila I feel
so rocky, oh man.
(horn blows)
Aiee!
- [Tom] There's a bug
on your windshield!
- [Joel] Hey this
isn't my fault.
I'm taking no kind
of pay cut for this.
- [Crow] Now if you'll look out
the left side of your train
you'll see the right
side of the train.
- [Tom] Canned people.
Scorpions just love trains.
- [Joel] We at Amtrak
would like to apologize
for any inconvenience
it may have caused
this rarely ever happens.
- [Tom] Oops not quick enough.
(screams)
- [Crow] That's gotta hurt.
- [Tom] I'm hungry for Mexican.
- [Crow] Don't run,
just look unappetizing.
- [Tom] He ordered a stinger.
Smear yourself with axle
grease, they hate that.
- [Crow] Now for you folks
playing at home keep in mind
scorpions unless genetically
mutated do not growl.
- [Tom] It's like a scorpion
battle royale happening.
- [Announcer] We
interrupt this program
to bring you a news bulletin.
The express train
from Monterey has
been derailed outside
of Mexico City.
Early reports indicate an
appalling loss of life.
- [Tom] Do you know
the way to Monterey?
- [Announcer] State that
monster scorpions have swarmed
around the wreckage
creating havoc.
One moment please we're trying
to get through to
the emergency area.
- [Joel] But first
perhaps you would
like to upgrade your pledge
from the $50 to the $100 level.
- [Announcer] Indicate
that many of the victims of
the disaster are so
badly injured there is
little hope of their survival.
- [Tom] It's called
death deal with it.
- [Announcer]
Ambulances, private cars,
trucks and other vehicles
have been commandeered
by the authorities
in this emergency.
We've received a verified report
from the scene of the wreck
confirming that 129
persons are killed
and hundreds are
unaccounted for.
Survivors report that
a giant black scorpion
has attacked and killed
the smaller scorpions
and is now headed
for Mexico City.
- We were trying to find you.
- What can we do?
- [Crow] Well don't ask Groucho.
- We're still not sure
how many of them are left
but I believe the largest
may be the only one.
With a lust for blood after the
wreck the scorpions went mad.
The largest killed 4 of them
and I think may have
killed the rest of them.
- Where is this scorpion?
- We've lost it in the
hills, 10 miles out of town.
- [Tom] But the boys are
dusting for prints as we speak.
(phone rings)
It's 11:00 o'clock,
time to eat now.
- Yes, it has been
seen, lets go.
- [Tom] Better eat first.
(upbeat theme music)
- [Announcer] Attention!
Attention the city
is under martial law!
- [Crow] Hey, it's
the Disney Channel.
- [Announcer] All inhabitants
living north of Takabaya
and west of Guadalupe
are ordered to leave.
- [Joel] Hey Panama
1990, what do you know?
- Listen darling you get in
that building you stay there.
- [Announcer] The Scorpion
has not yet reached the city.
It has now been verified
that only one giant
black scorpion is alive.
- [Crow] It's Panic
Day here in Panama.
I must be crazy to be
putting this much on sale!
- [Announcer] Completely
surrounding the
area where it was last seen.
- [Crow] Panicked young
schoolboys only $15.99.
How do we do it?
Volume, volume, volume!
- [Tom] Don't put extension
cords under loose rugs.
- [Announcer] Have
been thrown into a
state of panic adding greatly.
- [Joel] How many
college students do you
think you can fit in this bus?
- [Announcer] Vital to
the defense of the city.
- Rifles and cannons
won't stop it.
- [Major Cocio]
Major Cocio here.
- Yes?
- [Major Cocio] We
have narrowed the ring
one mile around the Sorrentes.
Operation is proceeding.
- Okay that's fine.
Major take them in front of
the stadium with the weapon.
- [Tom] What?
- Major Ortega.
Major Ortega, this
is Dr Vilasko.
Meet us in front of the stadium
with the weapon and generator.
- With what kind of weapon?
- [Joel] Is it bigger
than a breadbox?
- I hope it is a weapon.
Just now it is only a prayer.
- [Joel] Let's pretend
you understand.
- To move all the heavy
equipment into the stadium.
- Colonel Sanchez?
Colonel Sanchez?
Dr Vilasko here.
Move all the heavy equipment
into the stadium right away.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] France 1940,
the Germans cross easily
through the French
Battalions and Paris falls.
Millions run before the threat
of the giant Nazi scorpion.
Wait a second, this isn't Paris.
It's not '41!
I'm not Little Thomas!
- [Joel] Serpentine!
- [Crow] It's Panic Day's
final hours everything must go!
Every item in town is on sale!
Everyone coming in with a black
giant scorpion gets in free.
No offer will be considered.
Hot dogs and balloons
for the kiddies!
- [Joel] Oh hiya crabby.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] The carnage.
- [Joel] You are looking live
at blasted out Vilagro Stadium
where in just a few minutes
puny local authorities
will attempt to take
on a giant bloodthirsty
genetically bloated scorpion.
- The projectile
enters the throat.
- If I'm lucky Dr Vilasko
but I have never used a
weapon like this before.
- [Tom] Oh come on, you never
worked on a whaling ship?
- Then the insulated
wire which leads to the
cable and the generator.
It should give 600,000 volts.
- [Joel] That is if
we can find an outlet.
- [Tom] Fly monkeys!
Fly!
(cackles)
(screams)
- [Crow] Plenty of parking.
- [Tom] What the?
- You think it should
bring him in here?
- I hope so.
- [Crow] Gee if you're
making soup for 10,000
that's all you need
to make a great stock.
- You might need more
than one shot Major.
- [Tom] You can't
leave those here!
Damn frat boys.
(screams)
- [Joel] Meanwhile in Ancient
Greece the same war raged on.
- [Crow] In the Vatican Noriega
cries "I need more beef!"
Nuns load truck after
truck of tasty beef
in an attempt to quell the
hunger of the papal pal.
- Yes, yes?
- [Major] The scorpion is
following the meat wagon.
- [Tom] Sorta like
a surreal version
of the Chuckwagon commercials.
Yah yah!
(sniffs)
Is that you or is it starting
to smell like beef in here?
- There it is.
- [Joel] A fabulous
arsenal is assembled.
Tanks, firepower,
snowplows, Chevies huh?
- [Tom] I can seat
you up front sir.
- [Crow] Wow, you
know Dan Wachowski
really puts on a halftime show.
Hey when do the Elvis
impersonators come out?
- [Tom] Well the
missile didn't work,
let's send in the bulldozer.
- [Crow] I feel the
presence of the great white!
Watch for her to surface!
- The throat Major, remember
the white area on the throat.
- The head comes back
just before it strikes.
- Right.
- [Joel] Hit him right
above the silk scarf.
- [Tom] You beautiful
SOB, I read your book!
(gunshots boom)
- [Joel] I'll be Pavlov watch,
ding-ding-ding-ding-ding.
- [Tom] Could you use that
mucus shot a few more times?
Shoot.
- You missed.
- [Tom] You should've
used a spinner bait.
- [Crow] Now go out
there and get it.
(gunshots boom)
- [Tom] We only had
one shot for that.
Whoops.
- [Joel] I'm union I
can't touch it, sorry.
(gunshots boom)
- [Tom] One persistent scorpion.
- [Crow] Aw we missed
the first half.
- [Tom] Oh nice move but I
gotta wonder if there wasn't
a little contact with
the ground there.
That would nullify the play.
- [Crow] Let's roll back
the instant replay here.
Yep there it is definitely
contact with the ground.
- [Joel] Yuck, not again.
- [Tom] I wonder what he wants.
- [Joel] Got to make this good.
My babe's in the crowd.
- [Tom] The spear's
up and it's good!
Score!
- Turn it on!
- [Tom] Mexico 3
scorpion nothing!
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] How do you
boys like yours done?
I like mine crispy
on the outside.
- [Joel] While Jim
subdues the angry scorpion
I'll mix up a roux
for a tasty gravy.
- [Crow] Now while your
scorpions are being cooked
you could fix up a nice salad
that could be done when
you're ready to serve.
- [Tom] He's down for the count.
- [Joel] You touch him,
I'm not gonna touch him.
- Turn it off!
- [Tom] You laughed when
I started my soup stock.
(dramatic music)
Whoo little onion,
cayenne pepper,
whoo good stock, I guarantee!
- Now we can secure some
of the actual poison
from the scorpion eater right?
- [Crow] All right
serve the salad.
- A simple protection
against them if ever again.
- Hank Vilasko wants to.
- Gentlemen we must
not waste any time.
If we could all meet tomorrow.
- [Joel] Fresh from his
Broadway stint as Lenin.
- Hank, Señorita Alvares,
we have not yet finished.
Neither have we.
Oh we have.
- [Tom] 'Twas beauty
that killed the beast.
(dramatic music)
We better get out of here.
- [Joel] That
scorpion's not gonna
be drooling anymore
that's for sure.
- [Crow] Nope let's
get out of here.
- [Joel] Is that just a serving
suggestion by the way there?
- [Crow] I think so.
(doors clank)
- We finally got
through that one.
It's the end of the experiment.
It's time for our favorite
segment of the show
when we get to read some of
the really great fan mail
we've been getting up here
on the Satellite of Love.
- It's juicy self indulgence.
- Yep it's great and this first
one comes from a Kevin Covey.
Let's put that up on the
screen Cambot and Kevin writes,
"I enjoy watching
MST3K very much
"The old '50s and '60s
black and white horror
"and science fiction movies
are a passion of mine.
"The worse they are
the more I like them.
"Anything that gets more
than a one star rating
"in the TV Guide is
too good to be watched"
Well that says a lot for our
show doesn't it you guys?
- Says a lot about
self abuse too.
- Yep Kevin Covey.
The next one we got is
addressed to you Crow.
It's from Tony Hepdart
from Palo Alto.
He says "Dear Crow."
Let's have an extreme
closeup on Crow as I read it
"Dear Crow I think you
are doing a fantastic job.
"I find your commentary
for the most part
"insightful and relevant.
"There are times however
when it appears as though
"you are forcing the issue."
- [Tom] Hah sike!
- [Joel] "Just trying
a little too hard.
"I understand the
frustration you must feel
"given the fact that you're such
"a unique entity in your field."
- True I'm an artist
subject to moods.
- [Joel] "You must
feel as though your
"crow ness somehow stands
out as a glaring defect
"lessens your credibility
in the public mind.
"Because of this you sometimes
talk simply to be heard.
"Simply to say 'Hey I'm crow'"
- No I don't think so I don't
just talk simply to be heard.
I have a reason
behind my talking.
- [Joel] "Simply to say
'Hey I'm Crow look at me.'
"And this my friend
is dangerous stuff.
"I sense you are
slightly ill at ease
"at being the only
Crow host on TV.
"By trying to
prove to the others
"that you are indeed
capable of the task at hand
"you actually do damage
to your own cause.
"I realize the
pressure you are under
"and wish only the best
for you and Servo."
- That's enough, I think
that's great, thank you.
- [Joel] "These remarks were
not intended to be scathing
"but rather as helpful aids
to your future success"
- No, thank you very much.
- This is great.
- [Tom] I love this
part of the show.
- Thanks Ton, loser.
- What do you think of
the experiment sirs?
Take it easy there you two.
- What about the address?
- Oh the address we
always forget that.
Do you want to do it Tom Servo?
Cambot put it up on screen
for the folks on Earth.
- It's the Mystery Science
Theatre 3000 Information Club.
PO Box 5325.
Hopkins Minnesota 55343
Have the biggest
brain on your block.
- That's it sirs,
what do you think?
- I think the
swelling's going down.
- Yes and I think
you should file this.
Here.
- Bye.
- Until next time
Mr Skin On Wiener.
(soft music)